THOMAS MARKHORST

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Phone: +31 (6) 11052279 ♦ Email: thomas.c.markhorst@gmail.com ♦ in

Persevering and problem-solving PhD candidate with good communication skills, as a result of education, work experience and teaching background, graduated cum laude with a MSc in Artificial Intelligence. Strengths include machine learning and computer vision, experience in image enhancement, neural architecture search, synthetic data, neural radiance fields & 6D pose estimation.

EDUCATION

PhD Candidate Computer Vision - TU Delft (NL)

Mar. 2024 - present

• Researching deep learning techniques for estimating various properties of human bodies.

${\bf Master~Artificial~Intelligence} \ - \ {\bf TU~Delft~(NL)}$

Sept. 2021 - Aug. 2023

• Specializing in Machine/Deep Learning and Computer Vision

GPA: 8.7

• Graduated cum laude, taking electives in bioinformatics and combinatorial optimization

Bachelor Computer Science - TU Delft (NL)

Sept. 2018 - July 2021

• Received a 9.5 for BSc thesis at Delft Computer Vision Lab

GPA: 8.9

- Graduated cum laude and with honours following The Next Generation Robotics Honours Program
- Minored in Robotics at the Delft Robotics Institute

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

1. **Bosch** Computer Vision Research Intern

(Eindhoven, NL) Dec. 2022 - Aug. 2023

- MSc thesis on image enhancement and object classification for security cameras in challenging light
- Developed Neural Architecture Search to design models for mobile devices while maintaining performance
- Further refined the thesis after graduation and submitted to CVPR 2024 on my professor's request
- 2. BMW Group Computer Vision Research Intern

(Munich, DE) Aug. 2022 - Nov. 2022

- Adapted SOTA pose estimation algorithms to stereo vision thus reducing the dependency on depth cameras
- Developed a 3D synthetic data rendering tool reducing the need for manually labelled data by 90 percent
- 3. Krill Robotics Computer Vision Engineer

(Delft, NL) Feb. 2019 - Sept. 2021

- Developed MVP object detection and avoidance for a robotic system on the water and brought the first version to the market in 1.5 years
- Multiplied funding four times annually by pitching to governmental organizations and companies
- 4. Dutch Org. for Applied Science Software Engineering Intern (The Hague, NL) Feb. 2017 Mar. 2018
 - Developed a robotic vehicle controlled using a VR system enabling remote presence in hazardous situations
 - Built an automated camera system tracking sports balls used for soccer game analysis
- Sailing Institute Aalsmeer Senior Instructor

(Aalsmeer, NL) Apr. 2015 – present

- Trained over 30 adolescent instructors to become independent by instilling self-reflection
- Led teams of 10 instructors to work efficiently and pleasurable with 50 kids by applying daily stand-ups and group reflections, while also teaching my own group of 8 kids and collaborating with 6 other seniors

PROJECTS

5. 3D reconstruction of aircraft engines using monovision SLAM

 $May\ 2021 - Aug.\ 2021$

- Researched and evaluated SLAM techniques to reconstruct shiny surfaces in 3D to reduce inspection time
- Developed a hybrid between traditional feature-based SLAM and DL based feature matchers tripling the density of the 3D model

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Programming Python (1-6), PyTorch (1,2,5,6), NumPy (1-6), OpenCV (1-6), Java (6), Docker (2),

ROS (2,3), C++ (4,5)

Interests Sailing, Running, Hiking, Skiing, Salsa, Promotional product videos

Languages English (Fluent), Dutch (Native), German (Intermediate)